A Guide to the John J. Chandler Letters, 1863-1864
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
John J. Chandler Letters, 1863-1864
The Library of Virginia
23984b
23 leaves, negative photostats
John J. Chandler
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Lent for copying, 29 May 1953, by Charles A. Taylor of Urbanna, Virginia.
Biographical Information
John J. Chandler was born in York County, Virginia, 16 December 1832. During the Civil War, he enlisted in Company B., 55th Virginia infantry. Company B later was detached and made into Fleet's Artillery Company. Chandler also served in Johnson's Artillery Battery in McIntosh's Battalion. After the war, he moved first to Accomack County, Virginia, then Northampton County, Virginia, where he worked as a wheelwright. Chandler and his wife Margaret (1848-1921) had 4 children. Chandler died 20 December 1913 in Northampton County and was buried at Broadwater Church.
Scope and Content
Letters, 1863-1864, from John J. Chandler (1832-1913) to to his sister-in-law Ann E. Chandler (1837-d. by 1880) of Middlesex County, Virginia, sending general war news and personal news. He comments on the battle of Gettysburg, adding that he would never marry a girl from Pennsylvania, and on the siege of Petersburg.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Silas Chandler Letters, 1862-1865 (LVA accession 23984a).
Contents List
- Letter, 5 April 1863, containing personal news and war news.
- Letter, 27 April 1863, sending personal news and asking her to write.
- Letter, 19 May 1863, thanking Ann Chandler for her letter and sending news of fighting that he and his brother were in.
- Letter, 2 June 1863, sending personal news.
- Letter, 17 July 1863, describing the battle of Gettysburg and stating that he would not marry a girl from Pennsylvania.
- Letter, 21 August 1863, sending general war news and personal news.
- Letter, 29 August 1863, containing personal news.
- Letter, 1 December 1863, sending general war news and personal news.
- Letter, 4 January 1863, containing personal news.
- Letter, 10 September 1864, sending news from the siege of Petersburg, Virginia.
- Letter, 14 October 1864, containing general war news and personal news.
- Letter, 4 December 1864, containing personal news.